Guide to the Empire State Pride Agenda records, 1990-2013
Empire State Pride Agenda records, 1990-2013
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Empire State Pride Agenda records, 1990-2013
7630
Empire State Pride Agenda
20 cubic ft., 3 map case folders
Manuscripts, graphics, news clippings, photographs, ephemera and audio visual materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files, publicity items, programs for fund raising and political events, news and flyers on gay and lesbian issues; also, minutes (1991-1994), chronological files on Pride Agenda's activities, posters, t-shirts, stickers, and other ephemera relating to fund raising and political events.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Incorporated in 1990 as the result of a merger between two statewide organizations: the New York State Lesbian and Gay Lobby based in Albany, and FAIRPAC based in New York City. The Empire State Pride Agenda is a political organization that lobbies the New York State government for legal protection and equal rights for lesbians, gay men, and bisexuals. Libby Post and Mark D'Alessio were the Pride Agenda's first co-chairs of the Board, and Richard D. Dadey, Jr., the first executive director (following Lisa Parrish as acting executive director for three months). The new organization was more successful at fundraising.
Maintaining offices both in Albany and New York City, the first issue the Pride Agenda tackled was the creation of a New York City council district drawn in a way that included enough gay and lesbian supportive voters to make the election of a lesbian or gay city councilperson a possibility. This was achieved in 1991.
The Pride Agenda adopts legislative agendas each year and has lobbied on the state level for a bias-related violence bill, a civil rights bill, and a domestic partnership bill. The organization endorses pro-gay candidates for local and state office, and remains active in New York City politics. In July 1998, New York City mayor Rudolph Giuliani signed into law legislation recognizing domestic partners in New York City.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files, publicity items, programs for fund raising and political events, news and flyers on gay and lesbian issues; also, minutes (1991-1994), chronological files on Pride Agenda's activities, posters, t-shirts, stickers, and other ephemera relating to fund raising and political events. Also includes large numbers of audio visual materials such as DVDs, CD, and videos as well as the files of Joe Tarver consisting of photographs, news clippings and event files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Dadey, Richard D.; Piel, Candida Scott.; Post, Libby.; Parrish, Lisa.; D'Alessio, Mark.; FAIRPAC.; New York State Gay and Lesbian Lobby.
Subjects:
Homosexuality--Law and legislation.; Gays--Legal status, laws, etc.; Lesbians--Legal status, laws, etc.; Bias (Law).; Civil rights--Law and legislation.; Unmarried couples--Legal status, laws, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Internal Files
Box 1-2, 4-5
Alpha files
Pride Agenda Organizational and Board Files
Series II. Subject Files
Boxes 1, 5-6
New York State Civil Rights Bill, 1994-1996
Senate Bills
1993
Series III. Media Relations and Communications
Boxes 3, 14-23; Mapcase folders 1-3
News Clippings
Flyers and Event Materials
Slides and Photographs
Memorabilia
Series IV. Audio Visual and Digital Media
Boxes 7-13
Videos
DVDs
CDs
Other Media
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Internal Files
  - Alpha file
    - Albany Domestic Partnership Challenge, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Awards Dinner, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Co-Parent Adoption, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, General, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, Paula Ettlebrick, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Division of AIDS Services, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [Empire State Pride Agenda Folder], 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - ESPA Internal Notes, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Funding Lesbian and Gay Family Issues, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Gentile, Vincent, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Health and Human Services Network Budget, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
    - Health and Human Services Network: Meetings (Albany), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - History, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - HIV Testing--Kaufman--Final Drafting, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Lesbian and Gay Health and Human Services: $2 Million, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Lobby Day, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Lobby Day, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Lobby Day, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Lobby Day, Perry Institute, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Memorandums, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Minutes, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - New York City: Regulation of Sex-Related Businesses, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
    - New York Gay and Lesbian Legislation, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - New York State: Lesbian and Gay Health and Human Services Network, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Night of 100 Parties, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Papers, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Perry Leadership Institute, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Pride Vote, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Public Policy Agenda, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Public Policy Committee, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Publicity for Events, News, Flyers on Issues, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Publicity, Programs (small size) (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Sexual Orientation Non-Discrimination Bill, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Social Service Agency Funding, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Testimony on DAS Bill--City Council, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Welfare, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1997 Agendas, memos, flyers (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1997 Constitutional Convention (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1998 Sexual Orientation Non-Discrimination Act (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Flyers handed out at Pride Events in the city June 1998 created by Tim Sweeney (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pride Agenda Organizational and Board Files
    - Adult Establishment Rezoning, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Board Packets--originals, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Board Meeting, January, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Board Meeting, April 13-14, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Board Meeting, April 13, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Board Meeting, June 23, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Board Meeting, July 27, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Board Meeting, July, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Board Meeting, September, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Board Meeting, November 16, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Board Meeting, November, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Board Minutes, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Catalog of Trainings: AIDS Training Institute, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - CERF-PAC of Long Island, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Channel 14 Boycott, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Civil Rights, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
    - Correspondence (incoming), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence (outgoing), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence (re:conference), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Development Associate Job Search, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - Empire State Pride Agenda Statewide Organizational Directory, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Enoch Williams Committee, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Fax flyer to send to membership organizations" (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Fundraising Plans: Board Members, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Guide to Elected Representatives in Albany and Washington, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Hotels and Community Housing, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Information Packet on Sexual Orientation Non-Discrimination Act (S.425-A) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Invitations (other organizations), 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
    - [Irving Roast Negatives] (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Law on Human Rights, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Legislative Briefing, May, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Lesbian and Gay Community Service Centers, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Letter from Bill Clinton, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lobby Day Registration and Bus Trip, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Manhattan [Volunteer Registration and Senate District Coordinator Application Forms] (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Media File: June-August, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Memos form Dick Dadey [Executive Director], 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - New York City AIDS Case Projections, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - New York City Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project Program Description (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - New York City Proclamation Photograph, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - New York Division of Human Rights Press Information (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Newsletter, Spring/Summer, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Newsletter, Winter, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Night of 100 Parties Publicity Material, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Organizational List, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - PAC, General, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - PAC, Reports, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - PAC, Reports, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Pacheco Contributions, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Periodic Board Reports, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Perry Leadership Institute, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Perry Institute Registrant, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - [Photographs of FAIRPAC event] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - [Photographs of FAIRPAC event], [1988?] (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - [Photographs of Night of 100 Parties] (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - [Photographs of Night of 100 Parties], [1988?] (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - [Photographs of Night of 100 Parties], [1989?] (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - [Photographs of Piel, Candida Scott] (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Press Releases, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Pride Agenda Board, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Prom '63" FAIRPAC Event, October 15, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Training Manual by Citizen Action Campaign for Citizen Action of New York, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Programs, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
    - Program Book, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Publicity Materials, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Roast of Candida Scott Piel", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Room Assignments (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Ruben Diaz Affair, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - [Russell] (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - [Russell Negatives] (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Stonewall 25, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33-35)
    - Stride Pride Button, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Volunteer Registration Form (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Whistles (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Williams--New York City Controversy, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
    - Empire State Pride Bylaws (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Series II. Subject Files
  - New York State Civil Rights Bill, 1994-1996
    - Civil Rights Bill, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ESPA: Internal Notes, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters, Support, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Public Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Roll Call, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - State Law, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Strategy, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Strategy, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Strategy, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Strategy, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Senate Bills
    - Assessment of Discrimination on Basis of Sexual Orientation, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Assembly Bill 1336: Prohibition of Discrimination Based on Sexual Orientation, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Senate Bill 3126-B: Bias Related Violence Protection, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Senate Bill 6950-A: Gang Assault/Bias Related Violence Bill, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Senate Bill 7551: Emergency Health Care Fund, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Senate Bill 7608: Health Insurance Community Rating Bill, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Senate Bill 5227: Crime and Correction, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Senate Bill 1890: Civil Rights Bill, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Senate Bill 6580-A: Deletion of Gender Classification for Sex Offenses, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - 1993
    - ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Action Alerts, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Albany Lobby Day, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Andrew Stein News clippings, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Boycott Colorado, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Campaign Finance Board, New York City, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Comptroller Office, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Civil Rights Bill, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8-13)
    - Civil Rights Bill Background Information, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Civil Rights Bill Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Civil Rights Bill Information, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Civil Rights Bill Press, News Articles, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Civil Rights Bill, Signatures, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Civil Rights Bill (Active), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cuomo, Governor, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Endorsed Candidate Questionnaire, Albany, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Endorsed Candidate Questionnaire, New York City, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
    - Endorsed Candidate Questionnaire, Rochester, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Endorsement, Final, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
    - Irish Gay and Lesbian Organizations, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Ithaca/Tompkins Endorsed Candidate Questionnaire, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - March on Washington, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Multi-Cultural Education, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - PAC, Candidate Addresses, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - PAC, Not Endorsed Candidates, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
    - Religious Right, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - School Board, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - School Board Elections, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
    - Senate District Coordinators, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Volunteers, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Winter Newsletter, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Series III. Media Relations and Communications
  - News Clippings
    - Clippings Binder (1), 1997, February 1998-April 1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Includes memo and clippings from 1997
    - Clippings Binder (2), 1997, February 1998-April 1998 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Clippings Binder (1), May 1998-July 1998 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Includes memos
    - Clippings Binder (2), May 1998-July 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - New York City Domestic Partnership Clippings Binder, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Includes a memo to the ESPA Board of Directors about the Campaign to pass domestic partnership legislation in NYC
    - New York City Domestic Partnership Clippings Binder, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Similar to previous folder but contains more clippings
    - Clippings, September 1998-November 1998 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, December 1998-February 1999 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and Report, December 1999-February 2000 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Compiled by Roberta Sklar
    - Media Relations: Clippings Binder (1), April 15, 2000-September 1, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Includes clippings from October 1998 on the Hate Crimes Bill
    - Media Relations: Clippings Binder (2), April 15, 2000-September 1, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Loose Clippings, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - New York State Clippings Service, September-November 1999 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Envelopes of clippings
    - New York State Clippings Service, September-November 1999 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, July-October 1998 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Hate Bill Legislation, October 1998 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Oversize folder
    - Hate Crimes, October 1998 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - End of Season, September-November 1998 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - D'Amato and Schumer, September-November 1998 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Anti-Gay Legislation, September-October 1998 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Gore at ESPA Dinner, September -October 1998 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Hate Crimes, October 1998 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, August-September 1998 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, November 1999 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Sexual Orientation Non-discrimination Act (SONDA) Editorials, 1990s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, August-November 2000 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Hilary Rodham Clinton Endorsement Clippings, July-August 2000 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Elections, August-November 2000 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Health and Human Services, November 2000 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Sexual Assault Reform Act (SARA) Clippings, Octoober 2000 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Hate Crimes Clippings, October 1998 - February 1999 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Hate Crimes Clippings, March-May 1999 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, February-September 2000 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, June-December 2000 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, December 1999-March 2000, November 2000 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Elections, March-August 2000 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, March-July 2000 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Hate Crimes, February-July 2000 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Pride, June 2000 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Trans Issues, June-July 2000 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - SONDA, May-July 2000 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - End of Senate Session, June 2000 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Hilary Clinton at the ESPA Dinner, April-October 2000 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - SARA, June 2000 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, October 1999 - January 2000 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Summer 2001 - Events Press, April-August 2001 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Same Sex Census Articles, June 2001 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - SONDA - Religious Op-Eds, May 2001 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - September 11th, September-October 2001 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - September 11th, October 2001 - March 2002 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - September 11th, January 2002 - March 2003 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - State Fair, August-September 2001 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - SONDA - Editorial Originals, May-June 2001 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - DONDA - Articles, February-May 2001 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Obituaries, March 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - SONDA Editorials, May-June 2001 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - SONDA Letters to the Editor, June-July 2001; February 2002 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Rochester Dinner, April-May 2001 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Dignity for All Students Act Articles, March -July 2001 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Election, March-December 2001 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Pride, June-July 2001 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Albany County - Domestic Partnerships, August 2001-February 2002 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, January-December 2002 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - LGBT Network Funding, February, June 2002 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Dignity for All Students Act Articles, March-November 2002 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - New York City Transgender Bill, May-June 2002 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Rochester Pride and Spring Dinner, May-July 2002 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Events, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Elections, September-November 2002 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - SONDA, January 2002-January 2003 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - SONDA - Editorials, Opinions, and Letters, January 2002-January 2003 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - SONDA - Articles, December 2002 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - New York City Equal Benefits Bill, September-October 2002 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Fall Elections for Assembly and Senate, October 2002 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Fall Elections - Other, August-December 2002 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Family Court, June 2001-July 2002 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Special Elections, January-February 2002 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Local Domestic Partnership Initiatives, September 2002 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Obituaries, October 2002 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Fall Elections - Governor's Race, Opinions and Editorials, September-October 2002 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - SONDA Articles, December 2002 - January 2003 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - SONDA Letters to the Editor, December 2002 - March 2003 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - SONDA - Employment Articles, January 2003 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Youth Risk Behavior Survey (YRBS) Articles, October-November 2002 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - State of the State, February 2003 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Lawrence, Canada, 'Gay Summer', June-November 2003 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - New York Democratic Resolution for Same Sex Marriage, September-October 2003 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court (SJC) Decision Regarding Marriage, July-December 2003 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Elections, June-November 2003 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Network Funding, May-June 2003 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Equal Benefits Bill (EBB), November 2003 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - SARA Clean-up, Credit Union and Campus Bias, June-July 2003 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Gender Expression Non-Discrimination Act (GENDA), February, May 2003 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Safe Schools, Dignity, Harvey Milk, June-November 2003 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Jeanne Newland, May-June 2003 (Box 16, Folder 46)
      She had been denied New York jobless benefits usually given to same sex couples when following a partner taking a job elsewhere. Governor Pataki stepped in and allowed the benefits.
    - Obituaries, September 2003 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - James Davis's Shooting, July 2003 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Rudetsky - Santorum Fund, May 2003 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Hate Crimes, May-September 2003 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Staff Changes, May, September 2003 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, May-November 2003 (Box 16, Folder 52)
      Post-SONDA, Pataki, Bill Borman
    - Massachusetts SJC Decisions - Editorials, November 2003 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Equal Benefits Bill (EBB), February 2003 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Special Elections, January-March 2003 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Domestic Partnership Initiatives, January-July 2003 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - Alan Van Capelle as New Head of ESPA, April 2003 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - General Political, February, April 2003 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - Trans Issues, February, April 2003 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - Dignity for All Students Act, April 2003 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - Events Coverage, June 2003 - January 2004 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - Events, April-May 2003 (Box 16, Folder 62)
    - Victory! Coverage, February -April 2003 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - SONDA, February-April 2003 (Box 16, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, January-May 2003 (Box 16, Folder 65)
    - Network Funding, February-March 2003 (Box 16, Folder 66)
    - H & M Boycott, January 2004 (Box 16, Folder 67)
    - Jeanne Newland, February-March 2004 (Box 16, Folder 68)
    - EBB, December 2003-December 2004 (Box 16, Folder 69)
    - Marriage, January-February 2004 (Box 16, Folder 70)
    - Marriage, March-April 2004 (Box 16, Folder 71)
    - Marriage, May-June 2004 (Box 16, Folder 72)
    - Marriage, July-December 2004 (Box 16, Folder 73)
    - New York Town Meeting on Marriage, March-April 2004 (Box 16, Folder 74)
    - Spring Dinner, April-July 2004 (Box 16, Folder 75)
    - Fall Dinner, October 2004 (Box 16, Folder 76)
    - Tea Dance, Rites of Summer, June-August 2004 (Box 16, Folder 77)
    - Pride, June-July 2004 (Box 16, Folder 78)
    - Equality Network Awards, June 2004 (Box 16, Folder 79)
    - Elections - Federal, State and Local, June-November 2004 (Box 16, Folder 80)
    - McGreevey, August 2004 (Box 16, Folder 81)
    - Vincent Gentile, September-October 2004 (Box 16, Folder 82)
    - New Jersey Domestic Partnership Law, February 2004 (Box 16, Folder 83)
    - Domestic Partnership Registry, February-March 2004 (Box 16, Folder 84)
    - Marriage Protection Act (MPA) U.S. House of Representatives, July-August-2004 (Box 16, Folder 85)